So far, we've been talking a lot about velocity and position.
到目前为止 我们一直在谈论速度和位置
And the reason for that is because these two quantities are
原因是 这两个量
related to each other in three important ways.
在三个重要方面相互关联
First, velocity is the instantaneous rate of change of position.
首先 速度是位置的瞬时变化率
Now, we tried to approximate the instantaneous rate of change in
在前面的例子里 我们试图粗略估计瞬时变化率
the previous examples when we made delta T smaller and smaller and smaller.
随着ΔT越来越小
And we saw that as delta T got closer and closer to zero,
能看到随着ΔT越来越接近于零
our estimate of the true instantaneous speed got better and better.
我们对真实瞬时速度的估计越来越准确
Another important relationship between velocity and position is this,
速度和位置之间的另一个重要关系是这样的
velocity is the slope of the tangent line of position.
速度是位置切线的斜率
And what this means is that if we have
而这意味着 如果我们有
a single continuous graph of position versus time, like this,
位置与时间的单一连续图 像这样
and we want to know the velocity at some point like, let's say here,
我们想知道某个点的速度 比如说这里
then what we do is we first draw what's called
那么我们所做的就是先画出所谓的
a tangent line which is the line that just grazes the graph at this point.
一条切线 就是刚刚在这个点上掠过的那条线
So in this case, the following would not be a tangent line,
所以在本例中 下面不会是一条切线
even though it passes through the orange point it doesn't graze the graph,
即使它通过橙色的点 它不会掠过图表
it slices right through it.
而是会切断它
The tangent line to the point would look more like this,
这个点的切线看起来更像这样
since this line just grazes the graph at the orange point.
因为这条线只是在橙色点上掠过图形
And this makes statement number two a pretty amazing fact.
这使得陈述 2 成为一个相当惊人的事实
When you have a graph of position versus time and you
当你有位置与时间的关系图时
want to know the instantaneous velocity at any moment,
而你想要随时知道瞬时速度
you can just find the tangent line to the graph at that moment and calculate its slope.
你可以在此刻找到图形的切线并计算其斜率
Now, the third relationship,
现在 第三种关系
which is really just another way of saying these first two,
这实际上只是前面两个的另一种说法
is this: velocity is the derivative of position.
就是：速度是位置的导数
And in calculus, the derivative is defined as the instantaneous rate of change.
在微积分中 导数定义为瞬时变化率
It tells you how one variable,
它告诉你一个变量
like position, changes with respect to another, like time.
比如位置 如何相对于另一个变量发生变化 比如时间
And derivatives tend to show up in situations where we
而导数往往出现在
care about how various quantities change together.
我们关心各种数量如何一起变化时
So, for example, how much will my wheels turn when I turn my steering wheel one degree?
举个例子 当方向盘转动一度时车轮会转多少？
Or, how much will my acceleration increase?
或者 加速度会增加多少？
Or how my localization uncertainty change
或者 当我将传感器更新频率增加10％
when I increase my sensor update frequency by 10 percent?
我的定位不确定性如何变化？
In order to answer any of these questions mathematically,
为了从数学上回答这些问题
you'll need to use derivatives.
你需要运用导数
And if these questions or these three statements don't quite make sense yet,
而如果这些问题或这三种陈述还不太合理
don't worry, we're going to keep exploring derivatives for the rest of this lesson.
别担心 我们在本课其余部分会继续学习导数